谋杀
Murder.
神秘
Mystery.
死亡
The macabre.
是什么让一个花心热血神探
What is it about a heart-boiled detective femme fertile,
带着一把冰冷的枪
And the cold steel of a gun, keeps our bedside
让我们彻夜不眠的阅读
Lamps burning into the wee hours of the morning.
无论辞藻有多华丽
However the spell is cast,
今晚欢迎我们的文学大师
Tonight we honor a master of the form
一起庆祝斯托姆系列的完结
And celebrate the launch of Storm fall.
准备要洗掉它就打电话给我
Call me when you're ready to wash that off.
畅销的德瑞克·斯托姆悬疑小说
The stunning conclusion to his best selling
最精彩结局
Derek Storm mystery series.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen
有请悬疑大师
The master of the macabre,
里克·卡塞尔
Rick Castle.
她是谁
Who are you?
艾莉森·提斯戴尔
Alison Tisdale
24岁  毕业于纽约大学
24, grad student at N.Y.U.,
参与社会工作项目
Part of the social work program.
这是个适合社会工作者的好地方
Nice place for a social worker.
花他爸爸的钱
Daddy's money.
邻居打电话抱怨说音乐声太吵
Neighbors called to complain about the music.
她没有接
When she didn't answer,
所以他们派人过来看看怎么回事
They had the super check on her.
没有挣扎的迹象
No signs of struggle.
凶手认识她
He knew her.
甚至送花给她
Even bought her flowers.
谁说世上没有浪漫了
Who says romance is dead?
我说的  每周六晚上一次
I do, every Saturday night.
画点口红不会出事的
A little lipstick wouldn't hurt.
我只是随口说说
I'm just saying.
那么除了玫瑰他还送给她什么
So what'd he give her besides roses?
朝胸口开了两枪
Two shots to the chest,
小口径
Small caliber.
你们谁觉得看上去很熟悉吗
Does this look familiar to anyone?
没有  我不是喜欢诡异事情的人
No, but I'm not the one with a thing for freaky ones.
我只是好奇
Just give me a "Jack shot Jill over bill"
之后我就可以拍拍屁股回家了
So I can get my collar and go home.
但是做诡异事情要求的更多
Oh, but the freaky ones require more.
也会留下更多线索
They reveal more.
看着他是如何摆放她的  用花瓣盖住
Look at how he left her, covered modestly.
所以呢
So?
所以他花了很多心思
So despite all of the effort, all of the preparation,
让你发现不了性侵犯的证据
You won't find any evidence of sexual abuse.
从这些你就能看出吗
You really get that from just this?
这个  还有这个  我以前见过
This, plus, I've seen this before.
你见过吗  在哪里
You've seen it before? Where?
身上盖满玫瑰花  眼睛上放着向日葵
Roses on her body, sunflowers on her eyes?
你们都不读书的吗
Don't you guys read?
什么样的白痴
What kind of idiot
会把自己畅销书里的主人公写成被杀死
Kills off his best-Selling main character?
你是作为我的吸血鬼出版商问我吗
Are you asking as my bloodsucking publisher
还是我的吸血鬼前妻
Or as my bloodsucking ex-wife?
这就是你要做的吗
Oh, is that what you're doing?
断我的财路惩罚我
Punishing me by killing the golden goose?
行了  可能我是卑微还有目光短浅
Oh, come on. I may be petty and shortsighted,
但是还不至于
But I'm not that petty and shortsighted.
是吗  那是为什么
Really? Then why?
虚构德瑞克曾经让我很快乐
Writing Derrick used to be fun.
现在这却像是工作
Now it's like work.
上帝不让你工作
Mm. God forbid you should work.
我的意思是你可以让他退休
I mean, you could have retired him,
或是写他有残废
You could have crippled him.
亦可以是让他加入讨厌的马戏团
You could have had him join the friggin' circus.
但是  没有  你非要让他被枪杀
But, no, you had to put a bullet through his head.
是啊  真的很糟  头上还穿了个大洞
Yeah, real messy, too. Big exit wound.
别着急  德瑞克·斯托姆不是我们的财路
Don't worry. Derrick Storm is not the golden goose here.
我才是
I am.
我在他之前写过六本畅销小说
I wrote half a dozen best sellers before him.
是什么让你认为我会停下来不再写
What makes you think I'm gonna stop now?
我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
事实上新书不是9周前就应该出版的吗
The fact the new book was due nine weeks ago?
你不能催促一个天才
You can't rush genius.
天才  理查德  不是没灵感了吗
Genius, Richard? Try blockage.
我听说你这几个月什么都没写
I heard you haven't written in months.
荒谬
That's ridiculous.
我的消息可是很可靠的
My sources are very reliable.
好吧  他们错了
Well, they're wrong.
那最好是他们错了
They better be.
如果三周内没看见你
If I don't have a new manuscript
最新稿子在我桌上
On my desk in the next three weeks,
准备退还你的钱
Black pawn is prepared to demand the return of your advance.
你不敢那样
You wouldn't dare.
试试啊  有本事就试试
Try me. Just try me.
你知道  我已经还回去了
You know, I already returned that advance.
我花在跟你离婚了上了
I spent it divorcing you.
天啊  可爱鬼  谁会在派对上做作业
Really, doll face, who does homework at a party?
我下周有个测试
I have a test next week.
我也是  体检  也没看见我在看书啊
So do I--Liver function. You don't see me studying.
好吧  给我一杯香槟
All right, give me a hit of the bubbly.
要两杯
Make that two.
嘿  孩子  销量一定下滑了
Hey, kiddo. Sales must be slipping.
他们只供应软饮料
They're only serving the soft stuff.
爸爸
Hey, dad.
亲爱的  那么  妈妈
Hey, sweetie. So, mother...
嘘  小声点  我还希望交到幸运呢
Shh! Shh! Shh! Not so loud. I'm still hoping to get lucky.
你告诉金娜我写不出来了吗
Did you tell Gina I was having trouble writing?
我什么也没说  我
Oh, I told her nothing of the sort. I...
我也许提到了一些你这些天花的功夫
I may have said something about spending your days
穿着内裤在Belmont等着邮件时候
Moping in your underwear waiting for post time at Belmont.
但是你是个作家  正常的
But hey, you're an artist. It's expected.
我们说好的
We had deal.
我让你跟我们住在一起的
I let you live with us
但是你不能到处说我工作事
But you don't talk about my work.
有什么好说的  你什么也没做
What's to talk about? You haven't done any
-自从我搬进来  -奶奶
- Since I moved in.  - Gram.
-好吧  他真的没有  -不管我做过还是没做过
- Well, he hasn't.  - Whatever I have and haven't done,
我会很感激你不把它与我前妻分享
I would just appreciate it if you wouldn't share it with my ex-wife.
这没什么大不了的
Oh, what's the big deal?
等会  亲爱的  我找到目标了
Hang on, sweetie. I just got a hit on my "gaydar."
好的  没有戒指  让让  孩子
Bingo! No ring. Stand back, kid.
妈妈去钓凯子了
Mama's going fishing.
你应该经过我的同意
You should have me committed.
同意什么  让她搬进来
For what, letting her move in?
我觉得还好啊
I think it's sweet.
当我想堵住她的嘴的时候就不会了
Won't be when I strangle her.
你知道我只有15岁  对吗
You know I'm only 15, right?
你内心很成熟了
You're an old soul.
好吧  我和我的"成熟内心"可以等等
Yeah, well, me and my "soul" can wait.
当我是你这个年纪时...
When I was your age...
我不能告诉你那件事
I can't tell that story.
我看来  太不适合
It's wildly inappropriate, which, oddly, is my point.
你不想发生点疯狂的不太适合的事吗
Don't you want to have wildly inappropriate stories
那种你不能告诉你的孩子的事
That you can't tell your children?
我觉得我两说说就足够了
I think you have enough of those for the both of us.
生活应该冒险点
Life should be an adventure.
你想知道我为什么书里写杀了德瑞克
You want to know why I killed Derrick.
再没有惊喜了
There were no more surprises.
我确实知道每时每刻会发生什么
I knew exactly what was going to happen every moment of every scene.
像是这个聚会  它们都是可预见的
It's just like these parties. They've become so predictable.
"我是你的超级粉丝  你哪来的灵感"
"I'm your biggest fan. Where do you get your ideas?"
还有流行的"能在我胸口上签名可以吗"
And the ever popular "will you sign my 'chest'?"
我不太在意那件事
That one I don't mind so much.
好吧  我在意
Yeah, well, F.Y.I., I do.
就一次  喜欢有人跟我说些有新意的事
Just once, I'd like someone to come up to me and say something new.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle?
你喜欢签在哪里
Where would you like it?
凯特·贝克特探长  纽约警局的
Detective Kate Beckett, NYPD.
我需要问你几个问题
We need to ask you a few questions
关于今晚早些时候的谋杀事件
About a murder that took place earlier tonight.
这个有新意
That's new.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle.
作为一个畅销小说家你的记录还真多啊
You've got quite a rap sheet for a best-Selling author.
扰乱治安
Disorderly conduct,
拒捕
Uh, resisting arrest?
小孩就是小孩
Boys will be boys.
有记录你偷过警察的一匹巡逻马
It says here that you stole a police horse?
是的
Borrowed.
那时还是裸体
Ah. And you were nude at the time.
那时是春天
It was spring.
还有  每一次  指控都被撤消了
And every time, the charges were dropped.
我能说什么呢
What can I say?
市长是我的粉丝
The mayor is a fan.
但是如果能让你感觉好一点
But if it makes you feel any better,
我很高兴能让你打我一顿
I'd be happy to let you spank me.
这就是你那套"坏小孩的魅力"
Mr. Castle, this whole "bad boy charm" thing that you've got going
对别人可能管用
Might work for bimbettes and celebutantes.
我  为了生活在工作
Me? I work for a living,
所以你是我的世界中两个角色中的一个
So that makes you one of two things in my world
一个是让我生活轻松一点的
Either the guy who makes my life easier
或是让我生活艰难一点的
Or the guy who makes my life harder.
你不会愿意成为让我生活艰难的人
You do not want to be the guy who makes my life harder.
好吧
Okay.
艾莉森·提斯戴尔
Alison Tisdale,
地产巨头乔纳森·提斯戴尔的女儿
Daughter of real estate mogul Jonathan Tisdale.
-她很可爱  -她死了
- She's cute.  - She's dead.
你遇见过她吗  签售会或是慈善活动
Did you ever meet her? Book signing? Charity event?
很有可能  她不在我的小黑本里
It's possible. She's not in my little black book,
如果这是你们要问的
If that's what you're asking.
这个家伙呢
What about this guy?
马文·费斯克  小案件律师
Marvin Fisk, small claims lawyer.
我的大多数案子都比较大
Most of my claims tend to be on the, um, large side.
那么这与我有什么关系呢
So what's this got to do with me?
被发现两周前在办公室被谋杀
Fisk was found murdered in his office two weeks ago.
我没把它们联系在一起
I didn't put it together
直到我今晚看见的案发现场
Until we saw the Tisdale crime scene tonight.
"花葬"
"Flowers for your grave."
这是我们发现的马文·费斯克
And this is how we found Marvin Fisk,
正是"平静地狱"
Right out of "hell hath no fury."
看上去像我的粉丝
Looks like I have a fan.
一个非常危险的粉丝
Yeah, a really deranged fan.
你看起来对我没危险啊
Oh, you don't look deranged to me.
什么
What?
"平静地狱"
"Hell hath no fury"
愤怒的女巫为血而来
Angry wiccans out for blood.
得了  只有最忠实的卡塞尔迷才会看
Come on. Only hard-core Castle groupies read that one.
有这样的人写信给你吗
Do any of these groupies ever write you letters?
骚扰信
Disturbing letters?
所有我的粉丝写的信都是骚扰信
Oh, all my fan mail is disturbing.
这是职业病
It's an occupational hazard.
因为有时在这样的案件里  我们发现
Because sometimes in cases like this, we find that the
-凶手试图  -试图联系他着迷的事物
- Killer attempts to - Killer attempts to contact the subject of his obsession.
我也精通精神病方面
I'm also pretty well-Versed in psychopathic methodologies.
另一个职业病
Another occupational hazard.
你知道你的眼睛很漂亮吗
And do you know you have gorgeous eyes?
所以我猜你不会反对我们查看你的邮件
So I take it that you won't have any objection to us going through your mail?
随便
Knock yourself out.
我可以得到这个的复印稿吗
Can I get copies of those?
复印稿
Copies?
我会玩扑克游戏  与其他作家一起
I have this poker game. It's mostly other writers
你知道佩特森·加诺  畅销书作家
Patterson Connell You know, best-sellers.
你不会了解这会使他们多嫉妒
You have no idea how jealous those would make them.
-嫉妒  -有人模仿我
- Jealous?  - That I have a copycat.
在我的世界里  这是很高的荣誉了
Oh, my gosh. In my world, that's the red badge of honor.
犯罪小说界内
That's the Criminal Cooperstown.
他们都死了  卡塞尔先生
People are dead, Mr. Castle.
我不是在问尸体  是要照片
I'm not asking for the bodies, just the pictures.
我想我们到这里就好
I think we're done here.
孩子
Hey, kiddo!
我在表演给看伯特在皇宫里怎么演的
I'm just showing Burt here how we did it at the palace.
他知道你的主打歌吗
Does he know it's your theme song?
准备继续吗  亲爱的
Ready to bring it home, ducky?
是的
Hey! Yes!
5  6  7  8
Five, six, seven, eight.
你错过了深夜秀了
You're missing The Late Show.
我早就看过了
I saw it in previews.
看上去我们有了新的领导人
Looks like we got a new lead.
他叫伯特  变魔术的
His name is Burt. He does magic.
-哇  -是啊
- Wow - Yeah.
期待明天早上他消失吧
Let's hope he disappears by morning.
在学校的午夜
C'est apres minuit dans une school night.
难道你没坐上南瓜马车或其他什么吗
Don't you turn into a pumpkin or something?
因为你被警察带走了  没坐成
Not when your dad's been escorted away by cops.
监狱里如何
How was the slammer?
有人把你当成是他们的婊子吗
Anyone make you their bitch?
对不起  无可奉告
Sorry, switchblade.
还是你的  张嘴
Still belong to you. Baby bird?
-我已经刷牙了  -你的损失
- I already brushed.- Your loss.
那你想自己告诉我
So are you gonna tell me about it
还是要我自己去粉丝网站上看
Or do I have to look it up on the fan sites?
不  我们说好了
No, we had a deal.
在网上查找一切资料
Surf all the internet you want.
但远离粉丝网站
Stay off the fan sites.
说真的  爸爸  你遇到麻烦了吗
Seriously, dad, are you in some kind of trouble?
尽管我尽力的去惹麻烦
Despite my best efforts,
但是没有
No.
他们想我帮忙调查一个案件
They want my help on a case.
案件
A case?
很明显
Apparently
有人杀了人
Someone's been killing people
用我书上杀人的办法
The way I kill them in my books.
-这么恐怖  -是啊
- That's horrible.  - Yeah.
杀了多少人
How many?
目前为止两个
Two so far.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
是的  只是觉得毫无道理
Yeah. It's just so senseless.
谋杀通常都这样
Murder usually is.
不  谋杀通常有很多的原因
No, murder usually makes a great deal of sense--
情欲  贪欲  政治欲望
Passion, greed, politics.
说他没有理由
What's senseless here
是因为他选择了这本书
Is the books that the killer chose.
地狱宁静
"Hell hath no fury,"
以花为坟
"Flowers for your grave"--
我一些不太出名的作品
My truly lesser works.
为什么一个精神病粉丝要选这些
Why would a psychotic fan pick those?
也许就是因为他是个精神病
Maybe because he's psychotic.
走吧  该睡觉了
Come on. It's bedtime.
你明天就能想通了
You can figure it out in the morning.
那是什么
What are those?
卡塞尔最出名的书
Castle's greatest hits.
你们要去熟悉这本书
You're gonna familiarize yourselves
掌握所有的犯罪现场
With all of his murder scenes
我们才不会遗漏任何线索
So we don't miss any.
有录音版的吗
Got any on tape?
第一个受害者  男性律师
First victim--Male lawyer.
第二个受害者  女性社工
Second victim-- Female social worker.
这本书的某个地方
Somewhere in these books
一定能找到两者的联系
Those two are connected.
在凯瑟琳·贝克特的图书馆
"From the library of Katherine Beckett."
你有阅读困难吗  赖安
Do you have a problem with reading, Ryan?
嘿  帮他检查一下  你是一个大粉丝
Yo, check it, girl. You're totally a fan.
对  文艺作品的粉丝
Right, of the genre.
对  文艺
Right, the--the genre.
所以你脸红了
That's why you're blushing.
你几岁了  12岁
What are you, 12?
作案特征显示出一个低智商的罪犯
Profiling indicates a perp with low intelligence,
确实或者认为
Someone who has or thinks
与我们的作者有私人关系
He has a personal relationship with our author.
所以我们从这里开始查起
So that's where we start.
怎么了
What?
我整天跟死尸打交道
I work dead bodies all day.
回了家
The last thing I want to do when I go home
最不想看的就关于谋杀的书
Is read murder books.
难道你就不好奇吗
Aren't you curious?
好奇
Curious?
关于人
About how people
怎么能一次又一次做这种事情
Can do these kinds of things to one another.
看了卡塞尔的书
Whoever did this read Castle's books,
书上的某个地点
And somewhere in those pages
也许就是下一个犯罪地点
Is the answer to where he'll strike next.
好吧
Okay.
这是卡塞尔的全部邮件
Is all that Castle's mail?
他的粉丝很爱他
His fans love him
几乎跟他自己爱自己一样
Almost as much as he loves himself.
麻烦你把这些拿回去做简单的介绍
Can you take that back to briefing, please?
实验室有什么消息吗
Did we hear back from the lab?
有  现场采集不到任何的DNA和指纹
Yeah, scene was negative for D.N.A. And prints,
跟菲斯克的现场一样
Just like Fisk.
这家伙很小心
The guy's careful.
提斯黛尔和菲斯克有什么关系吗
What about Tisdale and Fisk, any connection?
跟你的偶像相比吗  没有
Other than your boy there? No.
他在这里做什么
What's he doing here?
也许喜欢上你了
Maybe he likes you.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
队长
Captain?
有什么事吗
Yes, sir?
卡塞尔先生愿意对这次调查提供协助
Mr. Castle's offered to assist with the investigation.
是吗
Really?
这是我能为我所爱的城市做的一点贡献
It's the least I can do for the city I love.
考虑到犯罪现场的特点
Considering the nature of the crime scenes,
我认为这是个不错的主意
I think it's a good idea.
长官  我能跟你聊一下吗  私下
Sir, can I talk to you for a minute, in private?
不
Nope.
怎么了
What?
没什么
Nothing.
只是
No, it's just, uh,
很可爱
It's cute.
我的意思是不是你在打牌的时候
I mean not if you were playing poker.
那时候应该很难看 但是
Then it'd be deadly. But otherwise...
我能问你一个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
快说
Shoot.
你为什么要来这里
Why are you here?
你不在乎那些受害者
You don't care about the victims,
所以你不是为了正义来的
So you aren't here for justice.
你不在乎那个家伙模仿你的书
You don't care that the guy's aping your books,
所以你也不是因为被激怒了来到这的
So you aren't here 'cause you're outraged.
到底是为了什么  里克
So what is it, Rick?
你来捣乱的吗
Are you here to annoy?
我来这是为了故事
I'm here for the story.
故事
The story?
为什么会有这样的人
Why those people?
为什么会有这样的凶手
Why those murders?
有时候根本就没有故事
Sometimes there is no story.
有时候那些家伙就是精神有问题
Sometimes the guy is just a psychopath.
总会有一个故事的
There's always a story,
总会有一连串的事件
Always a chain of events
让所有事情都变得有因可循
That makes everything make sense.
就拿你来举例
Take you, for example.
正常情况下
Under normal circumstances
你应该不会在这里
You should not be here.
如此聪明  如此美貌的女人
Most smart, good-looking women
应该是律师  而不是警察
Become lawyers, not cops.
然而  你在这
And yet, here you are.
为什么
Why?
我不知道  里克
I don't know, Rick.
你是小说家
You're the novelist.
你告诉我
You tell me.
好  你不是乡巴佬
Well, you're not bridge and tunnel.
从你的说话听不出你是哪个区的
No trace of the boroughs when you talk,
这就是说你是曼哈顿的
So that means Manhattan,
意味着金钱
That means money.
你上过大学
You went to college,
可能还是一个好大学
Probably a pretty good one.
你有的选择
You had options.
对  你有很多选择
Yeah, you had lots of options--
更好的选择
Better options,
更能为社会所接受的选择
More socially acceptable options--
但你还是选择了这个职业
And you still chose this.
这就意味着发生了一些事
That tells me something happened.
不是发生在你身上的
Not to you.
不  你受伤了
No, you're wounded,
但没这么伤
But you're not that wounded.
不  是你在乎的某个人
No, it was somebody you cared about.
你深爱的某个人
It was someone you loved.
你很可能一直都活着这种阴影下
And you probably could've lived with that,
但是该抓起来的人还没有抓到
But the person responsible was never caught.
这些就是贝克特探长  你在这里的原因
And that, detective Beckett, is why you're here.
可爱的推理
Cute trick.
但是不要认为你了解我了
But don't think you know me.
重要的是  总是会有故事的
The point is, there's always a story.
你  你需要去发现它
You--you just have to find it.
我想我发现了
I think I just did.
实验室任务太多
Lab's got lifts off the letter.
谁的
Whose?
系统超负荷运行
The system's backlogged.
要一个星期才能完成指纹配对
It'll take a week to run a match.
一个星期
A week?
欢迎回到现实  超级巨星
Welcome to reality, superstar.
好  从没做过这么现实的事情
Well, never did much like reality.
市长办公室
Mayor's office.
你好  丹尼丝  我是里克·卡塞尔
Hi, Denise. It's Rick Castle.
-你好吗  -是的  他在吗
- Hi.  - Yeah, is he in?
-你等等  -谢谢
- Hold on.  - Thanks.
我说过  市长是我的粉丝
Like I said, the mayor's a fan.
里克
Rick!
嘿  大人物  我是里克
Yo, big cheese. It's Ricky.
-你还好吧  -当然
- You doing okay?  - Yeah, of course.
-有什么事吗  -我不知道你去哪了
- What's up? - Well, I don't know where you went.
我们到处找你
We looked all over for you.
你被一个女孩带走了
You took off with that girl.
这个人跟市长直接打电话了
The man's got the mayor on speed dial.
富人就是不一样啊
The rich really are different.
你想要他  他就是你的
You want him he's yours.
像你这样一个有控制欲的怪人
A control freak like you
也有你所不能控制的事情
With something you can't control?
不  不 那将会比鲨鱼专辑还有趣
No, no. That's gonna be more fun than shark week.
好了
Okay,
你将在一个小时内拿到你要的指纹
You will have your prints in an hour.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle?
这里一半的人都在等着要指纹
Half of the guys here are waiting for prints.
你不能插队
You don't just jump the line.
噢  我想有人感觉威胁了
Oh, I think somebody feels threatened.
-我才没感威胁  -不  我能感觉到
- I am not threatened.  - No, no, I get it.
我能打给市长  而你不能
I can call the mayor, and you can't.
我们有程序  有协议的
We have procedure, protocol.
是啊
Yeah
你总会在红灯的时候停车
And you always come to a complete stop at a red light
你从不会逃税
And you never fudge your taxes.
告诉我
Tell me something.
你放纵过自己吗
Do you ever have any fun?
把头发放下来
You know, let your hair down?
甩一甩头
Drop your top?
做一个"狂野的警察"
A little "cops gone wild"?
你知道我带了枪吗
You do know I'm wearing a gun?
贝克特  市中心区
Beckett, midtown.
他们又发现了一具尸体
They just found another one.
"舞会王后之死"
"Death of a prom queen."
维修工人一小时前发现她
Maintenance found her an hour ago.
肯德拉·皮特尼
Kendra Pitney.
她住在这栋大厦
She lives in the building.
好的
All right.
把她捞出水面
Let's get her out of the water.
你待在这里
Um, you just stay here
不要碰任何东西
And don't touch anything.
你好  我是理查德·卡塞尔顾问
Hi, I'm Richard Castle. I'm consulting.
理查德·卡塞尔  那个作家吗
Richard Castle the author?
是的
On my better days.
兰尼·帕瑞斯  法医
Lanie Parish, medical examiner.
我喜欢你的书
I love your books.
你知道吗
You know,
你对死亡细节的描写很有天赋
You have a real gift with the details of death.
我告诉过你呆在那别动的
I thought I told you to stay over there.
我感到孤单
I got lonely.
知道死因了吗
You got a C.O.D.?
没全部检验完还不能确定
Not until the full exam.
但不是因刺伤而死
But this wasn't a stabbing.
伤口附近没有血
Lack of blood around the wound
意味着她在被刺伤以前已经死了
Suggests she was dead before it was inserted.
口中没有白沫
No foam around the mouth
所以她不是溺死
So we know she didn't drown.
噢  你真有两下
Oh, you're good.
是的  她是先被杀了再布置现场的
Yeah, yeah. She was killed first and then posed,
就跟前面两个一样
Just like the others.
是的  我知道
Yeah. I know.
能跟你说句话吗
Can have a word?
有什么问题吗
Something wrong?
这是犯罪调查
This is a homicide investigation,
不是迪斯尼一日游
Not a day at Disneyland.
我下了命令
If I give you an order,
就希望你遵守
I expect you to obey it.
你还不非常了解我
Then you don't know me very well.
你知道吗
You know,
在我的书里  裙子是蓝色的
In my book, the dress was blue.
不要试着转变话题
Stop trying to change the subject.
提斯黛尔和菲斯克彼此认识吗
Did Tisdale and Fisk know each other?
我们还没有找到其中的联系
We haven't found a connection.
为什么这么问
Why?
那动机呢
What about motive?
他是一个连环杀手
He's a serial killer.
不需要动机
He doesn't need motive.
我是贝克特  好的
Beckett. Okay.
他们找到了吻合的指纹
They got a match off the print.
凯尔·卡博特  他在布鲁克林
Kyle Cabot--He's in Brooklyn.
逮捕他
We got him.
-待在这  -我保证
- Stay here.  - Scout's honor.
凯尔·卡博特  纽约警察  开门
Kyle Cabot! NYPD! Open up!
凯尔·卡博特  纽约警察
Kyle Cabot! NYPD!
房间没人  房间没人
Room clear. Room clear.
安全
All clear.
你应该邀请他加入你的读书俱乐部
You should invite him to join your book club.
贝克特  你快过来看下
Beckett! You gotta see this.
好诡异
Oh, that's creepy.
我可从没当过童子军
I was never a scout.
贝克特  来看
Hey, Beckett.
艾莉森的上衣
Alison's blouse.
看上去他喜欢收集战利品
I'm guessing he kept trophies.
点22口径
.22 caliber.
举起手来
Show me your hands!
Hands in the air!
把手举起来Cabot  把手举起来
Let us see your hands, Cabot! Let me see your hands!
他还是什么都不说
He's still not speaking.
州医疗记录上说
State medical records indicate
他患有广泛性发育障碍
He's got pervasive developmental disorder.
难怪他会那样执着于我
Well, that explains his fixation with me.
广泛性发育障碍症状之一是
P.D.D. sometimes manifests
对某一物体所表现出的执着
In an obsession with a single subject.
你的超级粉丝还有着妄想症病史
Yeah, well, your superfan also has a history of delusions.
猜猜他的社工是谁
Guess who his caseworker was.
艾莉森·提斯戴尔
Alison Tisdale.
是的
Yeah.
她的文件指出他需要大量服用安定
Her files indicate that he was on pretty heavy antipsychotics.
智力低下  认为自己跟偶像之间
Limited telligence,Thinks he
有着紧密的联系
Has a personal relationship with his hero
贝克特警探  看来你的剖析很正确
Looks like your profile was right, detective Beckett.
那就  就这样吗
So... what, that--That's it?
你还想怎样  证据都在他家
What more do you want? Evidence is in his apartment,
我们知道他与三个受害人都有关系...
We can connect him with the three victims--
两个去过他工作的餐馆
Two from the diner where he worked,
而提斯戴尔是他的社工
And Tisdale was his social worker.
打电话给检察官  替他找个律师
Call the D.A. Get him a legal aid.
-好的  -那也太简单了吧
- Okay.  - I'm, that's, uh, it's too easy.
读者绝对不会买账的
The reader would never buy it.
卡塞尔  这可不是你的书
This isn't one of your books, Castle.
一般来说  我们发现一个站在
Out here, we find a
尸体旁边的人  手里拿着枪
Gustanding over a body with a gun,
通常来说他就是凶手了
He's usually the guy who did it.
知道么 这孩子多年来一直
You know this kid was
出入于医疗机构之间
In and out of the system for years?
看起来他不像接受过正规的治疗
Doesn't seem like he ever got the proper treatment
直到艾莉森·提斯戴尔接手了他的案子
Until Alison Tisdale took over his case file.
她给他在餐馆找了份工作
She's the one who got him a job at the diner,
她的记录也表明他做得还不错
And her notes seem to say heas doing okay.
你还是把这些留给检察官去考虑吧
Well, you can let the D.A. Worry about all that now.
我们的工作已经结束了
Our job is done.
是的
Yeah.
你能把那盒子留下么
Hey, um, can you leave the box?
我明天再处理
I'll take care of it tomorrow.
卡塞尔  我挺高兴你书里灭了斯托姆
Castle, I'm kinda glad that you killed off Storm.
少了一个竞争对手
Less competition.
加诺  再加20美元
That's $20 to you, Cannell.
佩特森  你在虚张声势吗
You're bluffin', Patterson.
把你从电视赚的钱掏点出来
Cough up some of that tv money.
你自然就会明白了
And you'll find out.
到你了  里克
Ah, bet's to you, Ricky.
卡塞尔
Castle
-卡塞尔  -怎么了
- Castle! - Hmm?
-到你下注了  -不好意思
- Bet's to you.  - Oh. Sorry.
我懂那表情  写作没灵感了
I know that look. Story trouble.
是啊  你就不该让斯托姆死
Yeah, you never should've killed off Storm.
那是个极大的错误
That was a big mistake.
换了我的话  就会让他退休
I w-- I would've retired him.
或者让他残废
Or crippled him.
要知道  那人可是摇钱树
I mean, the man was money.
你肯定不会看到
You don't see
我用子弹打穿阿勒克斯·克劳斯脑袋
Me Puttin' a bullet through Alex Cross' head.
是  我的宝贝谢恩·斯库利
Yeah, my boy Shane Scully's
会继续替我的私家飞机缴交油费
Gonna be fueling my private jet
在人们已完全忘却斯托姆的多年之后
Long after people have all forgotten about Storm.
为这句话  我跟了
Oh, you know what? Just for that, I am gonna call.
到底有什么麻烦了   里克
So what's the problem, Ricky?
或许我们能帮上忙
Maybe we can help.
我在构思这么个故事
I'm working on this thing.
以一个著名作家为开场
It starts with a famous author.
某个疯子开始用他书里的手法
Some psycho starts staging murders
在现实当中杀人
Like the way he does in his books.
那也太自大了
That's pretty self-aggrandizing, isn't it?
我们谈的对象是卡塞尔
This is Castle we're talking about.
现场完全没留下蛛丝马迹
So... The crime scenes are clean.
没留下任何指纹  也没留下任何DNA
Doesn't leave any fingerprints. Doesn't leave any D.N.A.
可这个变态却给作家写去一封
But the psycho writes the author a fan letter
满是自己指纹的崇拜信
With his prints all over it.
结果把警察引到他的公寓
Well, that leads the cops to his apartment,
他们在那里找到了足以给他定罪的证据
Where they find enough evidence to convict him.
然后呢
And then?
-就完了  -就这样完了
- That's it.  - That's it?
是的 他们把他抓了
Yeah. They arrest him.
太糟糕了  难怪你大脑短路了
That's terrible. No wonder you're blocked.
还有一件事…
And here's another thing--
凶手在现场没留下指纹
The guy doesn't leave his prints at the scene of the crime,
可他却寄去了一封有自己指纹的信
But he sends a letter with his prints on it?
你把我弄糊涂了
Ah you lost me there.
心理扭曲
And what about a twist?
对啊  心理扭曲表现在哪
Yeah. Where's the twist?
是啊 没错 就好像
Yeah, right. Like, uh... like,
或许有人设计陷害这孩子
Maybe somebody set this kid up.
这就是你的故事需要的…
That's what your story needs--
主人公认为这孩子是无辜的
The character who thinks the kid's innocent,
继续调查  直到找出真相
Keeps digging until he finds the truth.
我有办法了
Oh, I have just the guy.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
这是小说家的习惯
It's a novelist's habit--
偷看别人的信件
Poking through other people's mail,
检查别人的医药箱
Checking their medicine cabinets.
你为什么还在这里
Why are you still here?
我只是来给你这个
I just came by to give you this.
一个小小的礼物
It's a little something to...
来纪念我们短暂的搭档关系
Memorialize our brief partnership.
别用怀疑的眼光看着我
Don't look so suspicious.
来吧  打开
Go on. Open it.
这是我新书的最新版本
I got you an advance copy.
我还为你签了名
I even signed it to you.
不是因为你是书迷
Not that you're a fan.
谢谢  这真的很
Thanks. That's actually kind of...
贴心
Sweet.
很高兴认识你  贝克特探长
It was nice to have met you, detective Beckett.
他不会吧
He didn't.
该死 他果然
Oh! He did!
理查德·卡塞尔  我们以
Richard Castle, you are under arrest
妨碍司法公正和盗窃罪名将你逮捕
For felony theft and obstruction of justice.
你忘记加上让你丢脸这条了
You forgot making you look bad.
你知道吗  有那么一小会
You know, for a minute there,
你真的让我相信你还有人性
You actually made me believe that you were human.
铐上他
Cuff him.
捆绑么  我的安全词是"苹果"
Ooh! Bondage. My safe word is "apples."
不用对他温柔
Oh, there's no need to be gentle.
你到底怎么找到我的
How'd you find me anyway?
不想想我是干什么的  我是探长
I'm a detective. That's what I do.
是我妈妈告诉你的  是吧
My mother told you, didn't she?
顺便说一下  提斯戴尔一案中的玫瑰花瓣
By the way,  the rose petals in the Tisdale murder?
是大花蔷薇的  不是香水月季
They're grandiflora, not hybrid teas.
我会记下的
I'll make a note of it.
对  最好如此
Yeah, you probably should
因为这意味着凯尔·卡博特是无辜的
Since it means Kyle Cabot is innocent.
谢谢  警官
Thank you, officer.
-你好  老爸  -你好  乖女儿
- Hello, father.  - Hello, daughter.
我真想说我吃了一惊
I wish I could say I was surprised.
这是我的错
It's my fault, really.
真的他从来就没个当爹的样
He never had a father figure.
不是那样的  妈妈
Oh, that's not true, mother.
我很有当父亲的风范
I had lots of father figures.
我想你已经见过蒙马利队长
I see you've met captain Montgomery
和贝克特探长了
And detective Beckett.
他们同意撤销对你的指控
And they have agreed to drop the charges
只要你能循规蹈矩
If you agree to behave.
别再干涉这件案子  卡塞尔先生
No more interference with this case, Mr Castle.
我说得够清楚吧
Do we understand each other?
是的
Yeah.
但你还是抓错人了
But you still got the wrong guy.
我真的
I... really.
亲爱的  你没必要事事都管吧
Darling, must you always have to make a comment?
不 不 不 不
Nah. No, no, no.
别跟我说  他迷住你了
Don't tell me that he got to you.
拜托  他哪可能迷住我
Please. He didn't get to me.
她才是
She did.
谁  艾莉森吗
Who--Alison?
马文·费斯克  第一名受害人
Marvin Fisk, first murder.
凯尔是在餐馆认识他的
Kyle knew him from the diner.
然后他杀了艾莉森  他的社工
And then he kills Alison, his social worker.
接着杀死了肯德拉·皮特尼
And then he kills Kendra Pitney,
也是在餐馆认识的人
Also from the diner.
然后呢
So?
然后  他从便利作案开始
So he starts with a murder of convenience
升级到对自己非常熟悉的对象下手
And then escalates to a murder of somebody he knows very well
然后又退回到便利作案去
And then goes back to a murder of convenience?
这说不通啊
It doesn't make any sense.
有人陷害凯尔  拿他当替罪羊
Somebody set up Kyle to take the fall.
那人又很清楚他对我的狂热
Somebody who knew enough about his fixation with me
利用这点来为自己脱罪
To use it to get away with murder.
就是说  我们要找的不是连环杀手
That means we're not looking for a serial killer.
我们要找的是一个厉害
We're looking for a good,
老道的杀手  一个有动机的人
Old-Fashioned murderer--Someone with motive.
你认为受害人之间有某种关联
You think the victims were somehow related?
那警方早该发现
Police would've found it by now.
我知道  如果由我来写这故事
Now if I were writing the story,
凶手多半只想杀死其中一个受害人
The killer would've only wanted one of the victims dead.
他杀死别的人
He would've killed the other ones
是为了掩饰这起案件
Just to cover up the crime.
你怎么能靠多杀两个人
How do you get away with one murder
来掩饰一起杀人案呢
By committing two more?
死一个人  你会寻找动机
At one death, you look for motive.
死两个人  你会找其中的关联
At two, you look for a connection.
死三个人  你就会找像凯尔那样的疯子
At three, you look for someone like Kyle.
死了三个  你就不需要动机了
At three, you don't need motive,
因为反复无常的连环杀手们
Because mentally unstable serial killers
完全不需要动机
Don't usually have one.
这跟"捕鼠器"一样没理由可讲
That makes about as much sense as "mousetrap."
我曾在一年里每周演那出戏8次
I did that play eight times a week for a year.
我仍然不知道它讲什么
I still have no idea what it's about.
卡塞尔是对的
Castle was right.
如果凶手想遵照他的书
If he was trying to follow his books,
那么艾莉森尸体上的玫瑰花是不对的
Then the roses on Alison's body were wrong,
费斯克应该是被塑料袋闷死
And Fisk should've been suffocated by a plastic bag,
而不是用领带勒死
Not strangled with a necktie.
Kendra的礼服则该是蓝色
And kendra's dress should've been blue,
而非黄色
Not yellow.
对一个狂热者来说
For an obsessive,
是不可能会忽视细节部分的
It would've been impossible not to get the details right.
如果不是他  那又该是谁呢
Well, if it wasn't him, then who was it?
凶手对他的预谋对象
The killer had to have known both his intended victim
以及凯尔肯定都知之甚详
And Kyle fairly well.
唯一一个对凯尔的狂热
The only victim that had any real knowledge
非常了解的人
Of Kyle's obsessive condition
就是艾莉森·提斯戴尔
Would've been Alison Tisdale.
艾莉森是关键
Alison's the key.
她就是凶手想隐瞒的真相
She's the one that the killer is trying to hide.
我们知道  她没有恋人
Well, as far as we know, she wasn't seeing anyone.
而她的其他情况都不符合剖析图
And none of her other case profiles fit the profile.
凶手多半知道了她的某些秘密
Well, somebody had to know something about her.
如果凶手是通过艾莉森才了解凯尔的
So if the killer found out about Kyle through Alison,
那艾莉森肯定就是预谋对象
Then Alison must've been the intended target.
有人想杀了艾莉森
Somebody wanted Alison dead.
我们只需找出原因
We just have to figure out why.
如果我得一次次地保释你出来
If I have to keep bailing you out,
那你得给我增加零用钱
You're gonna need to raise my allowance...
加很多
By a lot.
还有我的
Mine, too.
我是里克·卡塞尔
Hi, I'm Rick Castle.
我跟提斯戴尔先生有约
I have an appointment to see Mr Tisdale.
卡塞尔先生
Mr.Castle
他正等着你
He's expecting you
他现在还等着吗
Is he now?
事情其实不是这样的  这个
This is not what it looks like. This, uh...
好吧 其实就是看起来这样
Okay, this is exactly what it looks like,
不过我可以解释
But I can explain.
你来不
You coming?
艾莉森提起过自己有仇人
Did Alison ever mention having enemies
或者是被人威胁吗
Or being threatened?
大家都喜欢她
People loved her.
她只希望能让世界变得更美好
All she wanted was to make the world a better place.
我跟其他探长也说过这些
I told all this to the other detective.
我知道  先生  我们只是在跟进案情
I know, sir. We're just following up.
艾莉森认识的人中有谁
Did Alison know anybody
可以从她的死中获利的
Who could've profited from her death?
卡塞尔先生  或许我很有钱
Mr. Castle, I may be rich,
但我的女儿没钱
But my daughter was not.
她痛恨金钱
She abhorred money.
无论她有多少她都会捐给慈善事业
What little she had, she gave to charity.
谢谢您  先生
Thank you, sir.
提斯戴尔先生  "财富"杂志估测过
Mr. Tisdale, "Fortune" magazine estimated
你的总资产大概是1亿美元
Your net worth at nearly 100 million dollars.
是真的吗
Is that true?
我不经常计算这些
I don't check day to day.
但基本上是这样
But it's in the ballpark?
我一直都很幸运  所以我猜应该是吧
I've been lucky, yes.
谢谢你
Appreciate your time.
如果你出了问题
Wh-what happens to all that money
那些钱会怎么样
If something happens to you.
卡塞尔
Castle.
我的财产将会一半捐给慈善事业
Half of my estate goes to my charitable foundation,
一半给我的孩子们
And the rest to my children.
我是说  我儿子
I mean, my son.
谢谢你
Thank you.
刚才你那是什么意思
What was that all about?
他活不久了
He's dying.
谁  提斯戴尔吗
Who's dying? Tisdale?
你要热狗吗  我要热狗
You want a hot dog? I want a hot dog.
你想要什  啊  松手  松手
What do you take on your-- aah! apples, apples, apples!
-你怎么知道他活不久了  -好吧
- What makes you think he's dying? - Okay!
-你看到他办公室里的照片了吧  -对
- You see those pictures in his office? - Yeah.
他消瘦了很多 病态的瘦 不是自然的
He's much thinner now--like sick thin, not workout thin.
他女儿刚刚被杀害
His daughter was just murdered.
从他不断摸自己的头发可以看的出来
And the way he kept touching his
他好像很不自在
hair, like he's self conscious.
你觉得这是个线索
You think it was a piece?
非常确定  但他自己还不知道怎么应对
It's a good one, but it's new to him.
他最近一定做过化疗
The chemo's relatively recent.
他还化了妆
And he was wearing makeup.
想看上去健康一些
He's trying to look healthier than he is.
不想让股东们察觉
Doesn't want his shareholders to know.
他得了癌症  但这并不表示他是晚期
So he's got cancer. That doesn't mean that he's terminal.
不过如果他死了故事就会变得有趣
But it's a much better story if he is.
你跟她哥哥见面了吗
You interview the brother?
还没有找到见面的理由
There was never a reason to.
现在有了
Well, now there is.
-有芥末酱吗  -有
- You got hot mustard? - Yeah.
-哈里森·提斯戴尔吗  -是的
- Harrison Tisdale. - Yeah.
米奇  把这些货架装上车
Hey, Mitch, let's get these pallets on the truck.
我是凯特·贝克特探长  这是里克·卡塞尔
Detective Kate Beckett. Rick Castle.
我们想问问关于你姐姐的事情
We'd like to ask you some questions about your sister.
好  随便问吧  我们进去谈吧
Yeah, anything I can do. uh, let's head inside.
最后一次见她大概一个月前  在爸那里
Last time I saw her? About a month ago at dad's.
我到现在都不敢相信她已经死了
You know, I... still can't believe she's gone.
你们关系好吗
Were you close?
每个人都喜欢她  我是说  我姐姐她
Ah, everybody loved her. I mean, my sister--
她想被所有人认可
She just wanted to see the best in people,
甚至是那个杀了她的人
Even that kid who killed her.
她竭尽一切地去帮助他
You know, she did everything she could to help that guy.
甚至带他来过这里一次
Even brought him around here once
想看看我这里有没有工作给他
To see if I could give him a job.
但是你没有给他工作
But you didn't.
我不敢冒险  好吗
I can't afford to, all right?
这儿员工一团糟  我的债券也亏了
My employees mess up, I lose my bond.
我不知道  也许如果我帮助了他
I don't know. Maybe if I'd helped him...
结果可能会不一样
Things would be different.
知道你父亲活不久了之后你姐姐反应如何
How'd your sister react when your dad told you he was dying?
她很不伤心
She was upset.
我们都很伤心
We both were.
现在她死了  你可以继承双份遗产
Now that she's dead, your inheritance stands to double.
你想说什么 你们不是已经抓住凶手了吗
What are you suggesting？ You already caught the killer.
是的  不过他的律师要做的第一件事
Yeah, we did, but the first thing his lawyers
就是把他的犯罪嫌疑到别人身上
will do is shift suspicious to someone else
任何有犯罪动机的人
Someone with motive.
然后他们就会质问我
And then they'll stick me on the stand
为什么没有调查
And ask me why I didn't investigate
然后法官就会起疑
And then the jury will have doubts.
我们不想让法官怀疑
And we don't want them to have doubts, do we?
没错
No.
那你就要接受我们的疑问
So you'll have to excuse me for asking,
你姐姐被害那天晚上你在哪儿
But where were you the night of your sister's murder?
我在出差
I was traveling... on business.
事实上 三起谋杀案发生时我都不在国内
Actually, I was out of the country for all three murders.
你看我护照上的印章
Here. Check the stamps on that if it's useful.
美国护照
A U.S. passport.
货真价实
Absolutely unassailable.
我很确定是他
I was sure it was him.
Oh  别那么认真
Oh, don't take it so hard.
你不过就是个作家而已
After all, you're just a writer.
什么?
What?
没事
Nothing.
什么?
What?
拜托
Oh, come on.
他在撒谎
He's lying.
我能理解在他姐姐被害那天晚上
I mean, I get him knowing where he was
他能证实他在什么地方
The night of his sister's murder
但是另外两起谋杀案
But the other two victims?
他毫不犹豫  甚至没有问案发日期
He didn't pause, he didn't ask for dates,
他也没有检查日历
He didn't even check his calendar,
但是却准备好了不在现场证明
But he was ready with an alibi.
我的经验告诉我  清白的人不会这么做
In my experience, innocent people do not prepare alibis.
所以我没有说错
So I was right.
好了  给我日期和航班号
Okay, give me the dates and flights.
你为什么就不能承认我是对的
Why can't you just admit I was right?
因为你被骗到了  他对那个人深信不疑
Because he totally fooled you. He totally bought the alibi.
我有那么一瞬间怀疑了我自己
I had a fleeting moment of self-doubt.
怎么样
So?
他的信用卡公司确认过了
His credit card company confirms he
他在三起谋杀案发生的期间
Paid for three round trip tickets
的确买过三张往返机票
Dates coincide with the three murders.
所以根据信用卡公司提供的消息看来
So according to his credit card,
提斯戴尔的确在国外
Tisdale was out of country
等等  所以说我还是错了
Wait a minute. So now I'm not right?
这说明护照上的印章都是伪造的
Which means the passport stamps were forged.
我去给护照管理中心打电话
I'm gonna call passport control
让他们查查相关记录
And have 'em check their logs
他应该不会这么做
That's, uh, not how he would've done it.
你想到更好的主意了吗  Ricky
You got a better idea, Ricky?
第二本护照
Second passport.
他是怎么做到的?
And how would he get one of those?
有钱难道还办不到  相信我
Oh, with his money? Trust me.
在黑市上这简直就是小儿科
On the black market, it would be a piece of cake.
所以他用自己的护照出境
So he leaves the country on his own,
用第二本护照入境  实施谋杀
Comes back with the other passport, commits murder,
然后再出境  再用自己的护照回来
Flies out and then comes back in on his own.
完美不在场证明  完美犯罪
Perfect alibi, perfect murder.
但是几乎不可能做到
But almost impossible to prove.
除非你找到那第二本护照
Unless you find the second passport.
他现在应该吓坏了
Gotta be freaked after your little meet and greet.
盯好他  如果他有所行动立刻通知我
Keep eyeballs on him. if he moves, i wanna know.
有钱能使鬼推磨
The things that people will do for money.
这家伙杀了自己的姐姐
This guy killed his own sister in cold blood
又杀了两个人来掩盖罪行
And two more people to cover it up.
或者他是个极端的杀人狂
He's either a world-class sociopath,
或者这件事背后还有什么别的隐情
Or there's a lot more to this story than just money.
请转马克威法官
Judge Markway, please.
马克威  代我向他问好
Oh, Markway. Tell him I said hello.
不  他们正重建那个高尔夫球场
No, seriously. They're redoing the entire back nine.
我爱死那个球场了  什么时候会重开
Oh, man, I loved that course. When are they gonna reopen it?
法官大人 我不想打断 "高尔夫会谈"
Judge, I hate to break up "golf digest,"
但是我的情况真的很紧急
But I have an exigent situation here.
好的  探长  请讲
Very well, detective. Play through.
我们需要一个搜查令
We need a search warrant.
她需要一个搜查令
She needs a search warrant.
搜查哈里森·提斯戴尔的家和办公室
For the home and office of Harrison Tisdale.
哈里森·提斯戴尔  乔纳森·提斯戴尔的儿子
Harrison Tisdale? as in Jonathan Tisdale's son?
-是的  -对  他杀了他姐姐
- Yes. - Yep. He murdered his sister
而且还杀了另外两个无辜的人来掩盖罪行
And killed two more people to cover up the crime.
谋杀  那个提斯戴尔
Murder? The Tisdales?
你说这些最好有确凿的证据  探长
You better be long and straight on this one, detective.
哈里森的父亲已经是癌症晚期了  法官大人
Harrison's father is terminally ill, sir.
什么  我才在义演见过他
What? I just saw him at a benefit.
希望你有照照片
Hope you took a picture.
如果没有了姐姐
With the sister out of the way,
那儿子就会继承所有的遗产
The son will inherit all of it
不好意思
Excuse me.
这其中有很复杂的关系
There's also a twisted, emotional angle in there.
我不想拿那些狗血故事来烦你
I don't wa to bore you with the details.
但是豪门恩怨还有复仇
But family and vengeance.
真的很戏剧化
It's Shakespearean.
哈里森刚刚下班了
Harrison just left work.
他很有可能是去回家销毁证据
He's probably headed home to destroy the evidence.
你确定把他跟那两个受害人联系起来吗
Are you sure you can tie him to the other victims?
他姐姐的一个病人愿意帮助我们
Through a patient of his sister's
他曾经想陷害那个人
That he was trying to frame
这样的日子还不如在民事法庭
It's days like this I wish I was back in civil division.
谢谢你 法官大人
Thank you, sir.
谢谢  回头联系
Thanks. Soon.
提斯戴尔先生 你回家的真早啊
You're home early, Mr. Tisdale.
拿到住户名单了
Got a list inside.
很好  谢谢你
Yeah, thanks for your help.
情况怎么样
What do we got, guys?
看看这个  那小子的生意一落千丈
Get this. Junior's business is going under.
他欠了上千万美元的债务
He's tens of millions in debt.
不过有了他姐姐那部分遗产
But with his sister's share of the Tisdale fortune,
他不仅可以还债还能剩下不少
He stands to pay off his debt and then some.
卡塞尔  如果你要进去  要带上枪
Castle, if you're going in, you should be armed.
我的备用枪在前座的工具箱里
My backup's in the glove compartment.
我找不到  它-
I can't find it. It--
这次你给我老实呆着
This time, you're staying put.
好吧  贝克特  非常好
Oh, okay, Beckett. Very funny.
我没有开玩笑
Joke'sver!
拜托
Come on!
铐我一次  是我的失误
Cuff me once, shame on you.
铐我两次  就是你的失误
Cuff me twice, shame on me.
哈里森·提斯戴尔  警察  我们有搜查令
Harrison Tisdale? NYPD. We have a warrant.
等一下
Just a minute!
快开门  哈里森
Open the door, Harrison!
快开门  警察  我们有搜查令
Open the door. It's NYPD. We have a warrant.
他从防火救生梯上下来了
He's coming down the fire escape.
他在后面  看着前门
He's out back. Cover the front.
站住  警察  不许动
Stop! Police! Don't move!
卡塞尔  不要
Castle! No!
我抓住他了
I got him! I got him!
卡塞尔
Castle!
退后  退后  别靠近我
Stay back! Stay back! Don't come anywhere closer!
-蹲下  -退后
- Get--- Get down! - Stay back!
退后  不要再靠近了
Stay back! Don't move anywhere closer!
放他走 Harrison!
Let him go, Harrison!
-快点  -放松  放松  没事的
- Come on! - Easy! Easy! Okay. It's okay. Okay.
卡塞尔  你没事吧
Castle! Are you okay?
没事  不过这杀人狂需要吃片口香糖
Yeah, except psycho here needs a breath mint.
-闭嘴  -好好
- Shut up! - Okay!
哈里森  我不能理解
Hey, Harrison, you know what's bugging me?
如果你真的欠那么多钱
If you were that deep in debt,
为什么不向你父亲借一点呢
Why didn't you just ask your father for the money?
卡塞尔  你这么做可不是在帮忙
Castle! You are not helping!
你知道我怎么想吗  我觉得你问了
You know what I think? I think you did ask.
你向他借钱了  不过他不肯借给你
I think you asked, and he said no.
他一定经常拒绝你
I think he always said no.
作为一个白手起家的人
Self-made man like that, I bet he
他一定很鄙视这么容易就被击败的你
Thought you were weak for asking
他才是那个被击败的人
He's the one who was weak!
我一直想做出点什么
I was trying to make something with my life,
但是他只关心她
And all he cared about was her!
所以你才杀了她  不单只是为钱
That's why you killed her. It wasn't just for the money.
你想在他死之前惩罚他
You wanted to punish him before he died,
夺走他世上唯一最爱的东西
Take away the only thing he loved.
很完美的故事
That's a pretty good story.
你是什么人
Who are you?
哈里森  放了他 一切都结束了
Harrison, let him go! It's over.
还没完  还没有结束
It's not over, it's not over!
放下你的枪  否则 我发誓我要-
Drop the gun, or I swear to god, I'll--
看见了吗
Tell me you saw that!
你会把那个写进报告的对吧
You're gonna put that in your report, right?
手铐呢
Can I see the cuffs, please?
这里  这里
Yeah, yeah.
你到底在想什么
What the hell were you thinking?
你差点就被杀死了
You could've gotten yourself killed.
我穿着防弹背心呢
Well, the safety was on the whole time.
你知道 你应该告诉我的
You know, you could've told me.
那不就不好玩了
Where's the fun in that?
我想这样应该是结束了
Well, I guess this is it.
不一定啊
Well, it doesn't have to be.
我们可以  去吃晚餐  互相交流一下
We could, uh, go to dinner, debrief each other.
为什么卡塞尔  想让我成为你另一个挑战吗
Why, Castle? So could be another one of your conquests?
我也可以成为你的
Or I could be one of yours.
很高兴认识你  卡塞尔
It was nice to meet you, Castle.
真遗憾
It's too bad.
本来可以表现的很好的
It would've been great.
你永远不会知道
You have no idea.
你想见我吗  长官
You wanted to see me, sir?
是的
Yeah.
我刚刚接到市长的电话
I just got a call from the mayor's office.
很明显  你多了一个粉丝
Apparently, you have a fan.
粉丝
A fan, sir?
里克·卡塞尔  看起来他为了他的
卡塞尔. Seems he's found the main
下一部小说已经找好主角了
Character for his next set of novels.
一个冷面却机智的女探长
A tough but savvy female detective.
我该感到荣幸吗
I'm flattered?
先别急  他说还要做点研究
Don't be. He says he has to do research.
-噢  不是吧  -没错
- Oh, no. - Oh, yes.
-不可能  -贝克特  听我说
- No way. - Beckett, listen--
长官 他就像一个见了糖的孩子
Sir, he is like a 9 year old on a sugar rush--
完全不能认真做事
Totally incapable of taking anything seriously.
不过他的确解决了这次的案子
But he did help solve this case.
市长高兴  所有的长官都高兴
And when the mayor's happy, the commissioner's happy.
长官高兴了  我自然也就高兴
And when the commissioner's happy, I'm happy.
要多久  长官
How long, sir?
这就要看他了
Well, it's up to him.